(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
JOY
作詞：YUKI / 作曲：蔦谷好位置
Lyrics: YUKI / Composition: Koichi Tsutaya
いつも口から出まかせばかり喋ってる
I'm always talking nonsense from my mouth
Yes, No どちらでもないこともあるでしょう
There must be times when it's neither yes nor no
いつだって世界は私を楽しくさせて
The world always makes me feel happy
いつか動かなくなる時まで遊んでね
Please play with me until the day I stop moving
しゃくしゃ余裕で暮らしたい
I want to live with plenty of leisure
約束だって守りたい
I want to keep my promises too
誰かを愛すことなんて本当はとても簡単だ
Loving someone is actually very easy
ふわふわ遠くまで流れ流れて切なくて
Flowing far away, fluffy and painful
大切な想いでさえ忘れていきそうで
Even precious memories seem to be forgotten
たしかに君に会いたい
I definitely want to see you
百年先もそばにいたい
I want to be by your side even a hundred years from now
どんなに離ればなれでも二人を繋ぐ呪文は JOY
No matter how far apart we are, the spell that connects us is JOY
樫の木が揺れるお昼は
On afternoons when the oak trees sway
すぐに思い出してね私を
Please remember me right away
いつも口から出まかせばかり喋ってる
I'm always talking nonsense from my mouth
運命は必然じゃなく偶然で出来てる
Destiny is made of coincidences, not inevitability
いつまでたってもわからない
I'll never understand no matter how much time passes
約束だって破りたい
I want to break promises too
誰かを愛すことなんて時々とても簡単だ
Loving someone is sometimes very easy
たしかに君に会いたい
I definitely want to see you
百年先もそばにいたい
I want to be by your side even a hundred years from now
どんなに離ればなれでも二人を繋ぐ呪文は JOY
No matter how far apart we are, the spell that connects us is JOY
死ぬまでドキドキしたいわ
I want my heart to pound until I die
死ぬまでワクワクしたいわ
I want to be thrilled until I die
死ぬまでドキドキしたいわ
I want my heart to pound until I die
死ぬまでワクワクしたいわ
I want to be thrilled until I die
死ぬまでドキドキしたいわ
I want my heart to pound until I die
Wow wow wow WOW...
はい！というわけで！
Alright! And so!
みんな、ハローボ！
Everyone, Hello-bo!
ホロライブ0期生バーチャルロボットのロボ子だよー！
I'm the Hololive 0th-gen virtual robot, Roboco!
わー！
Waa!
Good morning! Good afternoon! Good evening! Hola!
ハローボ！
Hello-bo!
みんないっぱい拍手ありがとうございます！
Thank you everyone for all the applause!
というわけでね、本日はこちら！
So, today is this!
ハッシュタグ #ロボ子さん3Dバラードライブ で呟いてってください！
Please tweet with the hashtag #Roboko-san3DBalladLive!
というわけでね、改めまして、
So, once again,
ロボ子がずっとやってみたかった...
The thing Roboco has always wanted to do...
ちょっと今日ねなんとねあのマスクをしたまま
Today, believe it or not, while wearing a mask
こうずらしながらやってるんだけど
I'm doing this while shifting it around...
このバーチャルマスクね、あっはっは！
This virtual mask, hahaha!
そうなんですけれども... なんとね、水を飲みます。ちょっと待ってね。
Anyway... I'm going to drink some water now. Wait a second.
はい、というわけで...
Okay, so...
ロボ子がね、ずっとやってみたかった、
the thing Roboco has always wanted to do,
3Dのバラードライブが
which is a 3D ballad live,
やっとできるということで、
I'm finally able to do it,
もうすごいね、嬉しかったんだけど、
and I was so happy about it,
ちょうどロボ子が喉をね、壊してた時期でもあったので、
but it happened to be a time when I had messed up my throat,
もうめちゃくちゃ不安だったんだけれども、
so I was extremely worried,
でも今日はまだ声が出るほうだと思うので、
but I think my voice is coming out fairly well today,
ぜひ、もうロボ子は今の状況で精一杯頑張って歌っていくので、
so Roboco will give it her absolute best in this condition and sing,
みんな、ぜひぜひ聞いてみてください！
everyone, please, please listen!
もう3年もやって...
I've been doing this for 3 years...
そうなんですよ、ロボ子3周年。
That's right, it's my 3rd anniversary.
そう、3周年ライブの、
Yeah, for the 3rd anniversary live,
3月9日には配信ができなかったんだけれど、
I couldn't stream on March 9th,
振り返りということでね、
so looking back on it,
本日にリスケでやることができました！
I was able to reschedule it for today!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
無理せず頑張れ！イェーイ！
Don't push yourself! Yay!
サンキュー！みんな聞いてってくれるか！？
Thank you! Will everyone listen to me!?
どうだ！？おー！
How about it!? Ohh!
頑張れ！
Good luck!
バラードオンリーありがとう！
Thank you for the ballad-only live!
そう、そんなにね、経つんですよ。めちゃくちゃ綺麗だった。
Yeah, it's been that long. It was so beautiful.
そう、1曲目はちょっとロボ子がね、
Yeah, the first song was one that
結構前から好きだったJOYのね、
Roboco has liked for a long time, 'JOY',
えー、ユキの曲をね、歌わせていただきました。
I sang a song by Yuki.
メチャクチャ明るい曲でね、いいでしょ？
It's a very upbeat song, isn't it?
で、ま、バラードだからね、
And since it's a ballad live,
明るい曲もまあまあいいなって思って...
I thought upbeat songs were also pretty good...
あ、そう、ゴルシとね、同期なんですよ。えへっ！
Oh, right, I'm from the same generation as Gold Ship. Ehe!
そうなんですよね。そう、なんですけど、まあね、やっぱバラードって言ったら悲しい曲いいじゃないですか。
That's right. But, you know, when you think of ballads, sad songs are great, aren't they?
ロボ、好きな曲があるんですよ。
I have a song that I really like.
あの、奥華子さんの曲なんですけど、
It's a song by Hanako Oku,
作詞作曲が。そう。
who wrote and composed it. Yeah.
ちょっと、あの、すごい切ない曲歌ってもいいですか？
Is it okay if I sing a really painful, bittersweet song?
ちょっと泣いちゃうかもしれないけど、いいですか？
I might cry a little bit, is that okay?
ちょっと泣いちゃうかもしれない。
I might cry a little.
ハンカチの用意をしてくれたらいいなって思います。
I hope you've got your handkerchiefs ready.
というわけで、それではじゃあ次の曲を聞いてください。
So, without further ado, please listen to the next song.
『好きな人』、お願いします。
"Sukina Hito", please.
好きな人
作詞・作曲：奥華子
The Person I Love
Lyrics & Composition: Hanako Oku
好きな人は あなただった
The one I loved was you
もうこれ以上 優しくしないで
Please don't be kind to me anymore
あなたは友達の 好きな人
You are the person my friend loves
応援すると 決めたのに
Even though I decided to cheer you on
苦しくなる 気持ち隠せない
I can't hide these feelings that become so painful
いつも近くで からかい合って
We were always close, teasing each other
誰より話しやすいと言い...
You said I was the easiest person to talk to...
...気づいて笑って
...Notice and laugh
本当は泣きたくなってたよ
Truth is, I wanted to cry
どうして自分の気持ち気づけなかったの？
Why couldn't I realize my own feelings?
好きな人はあなただった
The person I loved was you
私の心はあなたでした
My heart was yours
きっと二人はお似合いだよと
Saying "The two of you are surely a good match"
平気な顔をして嘘をつく
Telling a lie with a nonchalant face
何もできずに見ているだけの
Just watching without being able to do anything
弱虫な私が大嫌い
I hate my cowardly self
叶わない恋だと知ってても
Even knowing it's a love that won't come true
この気持ちすぐには捨てられない
I can't throw away these feelings right away
あの頃にはもう戻れない
I can't go back to those days anymore
あなたがこの胸の中溢れてくるの
You come overflowing inside my heart
泣きたいほど好きになって
Falling in love so much I want to cry
泣きたいほど苦しかった
It was so painful I wanted to cry
泣きたいのは私だった
The one who wanted to cry was me
恋をしてたのは私でした
The one in love was me
もしも一つだけ願えるのなら
If I could make just one wish
一度でいいからあなたの好きな人になりたい
Just once, I want to be the person you love
好きな人はあなただった
The person I loved was you
私の心はあなたでした
My heart was yours
はい、というわけで、えー、『好きな人』でした。
Alright, so that was... "The Person I Love".
どうでしたか？パチパチたくさんありがとう！嬉しい。
How was it? Thank you for all the clapping! I'm happy.
この曲はね、そう、ロボ子が好きな失恋曲なんです。
This song, yeah, it's a heartbreak song that Roboko likes.
ロボ子が好き、って言うとちょっと何か語弊があるんですけどね。
Saying "Roboko likes it" might be a bit misleading though.
そう、いいよね、すごさー気持ちに迫ってくる感じなんだよね。
Yeah, it's good, isn't it? It feels like it really strikes a chord.
「好きな人は〜」って、「あ〜」「あ〜」ってなるよね、バラードになっていく。
When it goes "The person I love is...", you go "Ah~" "Ah~", right? It's a ballad.
ありえ泣いてますよ。
I'm seriously crying.
今日はね、バラードライブなんでね、みんなのこともね、泣かせてもらって、
Today's a ballad live, so I'd be happy if I could make you all cry...
ん？泣いてもらったり笑ってもらったりしてもらえたら嬉しいやつです。
...wait, or rather, if you could cry and laugh along with me.
なんか泣いてきた...嬉しい。
I'm starting to cry... I'm happy.
そう、そしてね、あの、今思い出した、これロボ子についてくるんだ、このカメラ、ちょっと待って。
Oh, and also, I just remembered, this camera follows Roboko. Hold on.
そう、これから、この後ろに
Yeah, from now on, behind me...
後ろに書いてある、この...
...behind me, what's written there...
「Robot Memory」っていうね...
...called "Robot Memory", you see...
ロゴについて話そうかなーってなっちゃったけど...
...I ended up wanting to talk about the logo, but...
この「Robot Memory」ということでね、
With this "Robot Memory",
まあ、ロボ子のね、配信で歌った曲がほとんどなんだけど、
well, most of the songs are ones I've sung in my streams,
まあそんな中でも、一部一部は、みんなライブとかでの、思い出の曲も入った感じの、
but among them, some are songs that hold memories from lives and such,
思い出の曲を歌っていこうと思ったので、
I thought I'd sing songs filled with memories,
せっかくだからね、ロボ子がやりたかった...
so since it's a special occasion, Roboco's long-awaited...
ロボッ... ロボッ... の、ん？
Robot... Robot's... huh?
あ、なんか緊張してきちゃった。
Ah, I'm starting to get nervous.
バラードライブだったのでね、
It was a ballad live, so...
「Robot Memory」っていうね、タイトルをね、大々的に付けてみました。
I gave it the grand title of "Robot Memory".
可愛くない？
Isn't it cute?
そう、始めはちょっと、なんか色々悩んで、違うのになってたんだけど、
Yeah, at first I was worrying about it and it was something else, but...
ちょっと待って。
Wait a second.
よいしょ。
There we go.
あれ？あ、これ、声聞こえてんのかな？
Wait? Ah, can you hear my voice now?
そう、「Robot Memory」っていうね、ロゴも可愛いでしょ？
Right, the "Robot Memory" logo is cute too, right?
そうなんですよね。
That's right.
あれ？運営さん、って今、あれ？
Wait? Management... right now... huh?
今これずっと声聞こえてる？もしや。みんな。どうかな？これ。
Has my voice been audible this whole time? Perhaps. Everyone? How about it?
聞こえてる？
Can you hear me?
あれ、あの...
Wait, um...
いや違う、あ、みんなごめん。
No wait, ah, sorry everyone.
今、本当は聞こえてないのが正しくて、
Actually, you weren't supposed to hear me just now.
あのロボ子が、あの咳き込みたい時とか、
When Roboco, well, needs to cough or something,
してる時に、あの運営さんに、こうやって「音をちょっと消してもらいたいんですけど」っていうね、
I was giving the management a signal like this to "please mute the sound for a bit",
合図を出してたんだけど、あれミュートになってないかもしれない。どっちだっけ？って今、
but it might not have been muted. I was wondering which one it was,
ちょっとね、あの焦ってしまったので、聞きました。
and I got a bit panicked, so I asked.
そう、咳払いをね、ちょっとバレないように、あのしてたんだけど、
Yeah, I was trying to clear my throat without being noticed,
あー、バレちゃったなー。あー。
but ah, it was found out. Ah.
そういうこともあるよね。
Well, things like that happen.
そう、ハンドサインが実はあったんですよ。
Yeah, there was actually a hand sign.
うーん。いや、バレてしまったら仕方がない。
Hmm. Well, if it's found out, it can't be helped.
じゃあ次もね、切ない曲をね、歌っていきたいと思いますので、
Then, for the next one, I'd like to sing a sad song,
ぜひぜひ聞いてください。
so please, please listen to it.
みんな呟きもスクショもいっぱいしてってくれると嬉しいよ。
I'd be happy if everyone tweets and takes lots of screenshots.
ピース！
Peace!
というわけで、それでは聞いてください。
Anyway, please listen to this.
炎。
Homura.
炎
Homura
作詞：梶浦由記・LiSA / 作曲：梶浦由記
Lyrics: Yuki Kajiura, LiSA / Composition: Yuki Kajiura
さよなら　ありがとう　声の限り
Goodbye, thank you, with all my voice
悲しみよりもっと大事なこと　去りゆく背中に伝えたい...
I want to tell your departing back something more important than sadness...
ぬくもりと痛みに間に合うように　このまま続くと思っていた
So that I'm in time for the warmth and the pain, I thought it would go on like this
僕らの明日を描いていた
I was picturing our tomorrow
呼び合っていた光がまだ
The light that was calling out to each other is still...
胸の奥に熱いのに
...still burning hot deep in my heart
僕たちは燃え盛る旅の途中で出会い
We met in the middle of a blazing journey
手を取りそして離した　未来のために
Took hands and then let go, for the sake of the future
夢が一つ叶うたび
Every time a dream comes true,
僕は君を想うだろう　強くなりたいと願い泣いた
I'll probably think of you, I wished to become stronger and cried
決意を餞（はなむけ）に
With my resolution as a parting gift
懐かしい思いに囚われたり
Getting caught up in nostalgic thoughts
残酷な世界に泣き叫んで
Crying out to a cruel world
大人になるほど増えていく
They increase the more I become an adult
もう何一つだって失いたくないから
Because I don't want to lose even one thing anymore
滲み飲まれ落ちてしまえば
If I sink and am swallowed up,
痛みを感じなくなるけれど
I won't feel the pain anymore, but...
君の言葉 君の願い
Your words, your wishes...
僕は守り抜くと誓ったんだ
I swore to protect them to the end.
音を立てて崩れ落ちて行く
Crumbling down with a sound,
一つだけの かけがえのない世界
The one and only irreplaceable world.
手を伸ばし抱き止めた 激しい光の束
I reached out and held tight a fierce bundle of light.
輝いて消えてった 未来のために
It shone and then vanished for the sake of the future.
託された幸せと 約束を越えて行く
I'll go beyond the happiness and promise entrusted to me.
振り返らずに進むから
I'll move forward without looking back.
前だけ向いて叫ぶから
I'll shout while looking only ahead.
心に炎を灯して
With a flame lit in my heart,
遠い未来まで……
Into the far-off future...
はいということで炎でした。
And that was 'Homura'.
聞いてくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for listening.
パチパチサンキュー！
*Clap clap* Thank you!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
あー緊張してきた。もうすごい緊張しちゃうね今日。
Phew, I'm getting nervous. I'm really nervous today.
結構これ今、はっ！
Wait, I just realized... Ah!
もう25分経ったって、マジか。
It's already been 25 minutes? Seriously?
すごい早いですねー。
Time is flying by.
あ、しー、ですよみんな。気づいてないよねー。
Ah, shh, everyone. You didn't notice, did you?
はいということでね、もう30分ということで、
So, we're already at the 30-minute mark.
まだまだ曲はね実は用意しているし、
I actually have more songs prepared,
今日はなんと告知もね用意してるので、
and I even have an announcement today!
告知は後半戦楽しみにしていてください。うん。
So look forward to that in the second half. Yep.
ということでですね、次の曲も悲しい曲になってしまう、
And so, the next song is another sad one,
切ない胸がギュッとなってしまう曲なんだけどねー。
one that makes your heart feel tight.
やっぱりボカロひとつ歌いたいなって思ってたので、
I really wanted to sing a Vocaloid song,
今回はこれを歌いたいと思います。
so I've chosen this one for today.
それでは聴いてください。rain stops, good-bye。
Please listen to: 'rain stops, good-bye'.
rain stops, good-bye
作詞・作曲：におP
Lyrics/Composition: NioP
面倒だと思いながら
While thinking it was a hassle,
君は僕にキスをした
you kissed me.
泣き止まない雨は穏やか
The rain that won't stop crying is gentle.
傘を閉じて二人濡れた
Closing the umbrella, we both got wet.
その声に もう少し
By that voice, a little longer...
抱かれていたいな
I want to be held.
愛してる
I love you.
今少し口が止まったけど
My mouth stopped for a moment, but...
叫んだ思いは
The thoughts I shouted out...
きっと雨と一緒に
will surely be with the rain.
…排水溝へ流れるように
...Flowing into the drain
どれだけ素敵な歌に乗せたって
No matter how wonderful a song I put them in
届かない…
They won't reach you...
雨が止み　君はまた
The rain stops, and you
僕に背を向け歩きだす
Turn your back on me and start walking
何にも君は言わずに
Without saying a word
僕も特に何も言わず
And I, too, say nothing special
照りつける太陽に
To the blazing sun
痛みを覚えて
I feel pain
濡れた髪が乾くまで
Until my wet hair dries
ここで立ち尽くしたんだ
I just stood here
確かなことから逃げてつまづいて
Running away from certainties, stumbling
転んだ時には空が見えた
When I fell, I could see the sky
冷たい雨にも嫌がらず打たれた
Being hit by the cold rain without minding it
君には届かない
I can't reach you
叫んだ思いはきっと雨と一緒に
My shouted feelings, surely, with the rain
排水溝へ流れるように
Flowing into the drain
どれだけ素敵な歌に乗せたって
No matter how wonderful a song I put them in
届かない
They won't reach you
緑が舞う日も茜に染まる日も
On days when green dances, on days dyed in madder red
お隣には君はいない
You aren't by my side
それでも確かに胸が騒いでる
Even so, my heart is surely racing
君のいる方へ
Toward where you are
私もやめた　世界征服やめた
I quit too, I gave up on world conquest
今日のごはん　考えるので精一杯
I'm busy enough just thinking about today's meal
バーモント・キッス
作詞：真部脩一・Tica・α ／ 作曲：真部脩一
Vermont Kiss
Lyrics: Shuichi Mabe, Tica α / Composition: Shuichi Mabe
もうやめた　二重生活やめた
I'm done with it, I quit the double life
今日からは　掃除洗濯　精一杯
From today, I'll do my best at cleaning and laundry
冬の香りの　雑木林を抜けて
Going through the mixed forest with the scent of winter
淹れたて　熱い紅茶も精一杯
Freshly brewed hot tea is also as much as I can handle
もうダメだ　その日暮らしは嫌だ
It's no good, I don't want to live day-to-day anymore
ラブレター　渡せないのも精一杯
I'm giving it my all, even though I can't deliver the love letter
恋の微熱　37度5分
Love's slight fever, 37.5 degrees
平熱　36度2分
Normal temperature, 36.2 degrees
私もやめた　破壊工作やめた
I quit too, I gave up on sabotage
妙な予感　振り払うので精一杯
I'm doing my best to shake off a strange premonition
もうやめた　無駄な抵抗やめた
I'm done with it, I quit the futile resistance
甘く　危険な日々にセイ・グッバイ
Say goodbye to the sweet and dangerous days
恋の微熱　37度5分
Love's slight fever, 37.5 degrees
平熱　36度2分
Normal temperature, 36.2 degrees
恋の微熱　37度5分
Love's slight fever, 37.5 degrees
高熱　38度2分
High fever, 38.2 degrees
とろけるキッスは誰のため
Who is the melting kiss for?
おざなりキッスは誰にする
Who do you give a perfunctory kiss to?
恥じらいキッスは彼のため
The shy kiss is for him
蜂蜜キッスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキッスは誰のため
Who is the melting kiss for?
おざなりキッスは誰にする
Who do you give a perfunctory kiss to?
恥じらいキッスは彼のため
The shy kiss is for him
蜂蜜キッスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキッスは誰のため
Who is the melting kiss for?
おざなりキッスは誰にする
Who do you give a perfunctory kiss to?
恥じらいキッスは彼のため
The shy kiss is for him
蜂蜜キッスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキッスは誰のため
Who is the melting kiss for?
おざなりキッスは誰にする
Who do you give a perfunctory kiss to?
恥じらいキッスは彼のため
The shy kiss is for him
蜂蜜キッスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキッスは誰のため
Who is the melting kiss for?
おざなりキッスは誰にする
Who do you give a perfunctory kiss to?
恥じらいキッスは彼のため
The shy kiss is for him
蜂蜜キッスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキッスは誰のため...
Who is the melting kiss for...
キスは誰にする？
Who will you kiss?
恥じらいキスは彼のため
A shy kiss is for him
蜂蜜キスを神様に
A honey kiss to God
はい、というわけで
Alright, so then...
バーモント・キスでした
That was "Vermont Kiss."
この曲、覚えててくれてる人いますか？
Does anyone remember this song?
ロボ子はこの曲をね、アレンジバージョンでなんですけど
I've actually posted an arranged version of this song...
過去に動画で投稿してるんです
...as a video in the past.
気になってくれた人はね、ぜひぜひ動画の方も見ていただけると嬉しいな
If you're interested, I'd be happy if you check out the video too.
そして、覚えてるよ、嬉しい、覚えてる。そう誕生日のやつだね
And, "I remember," "happy," "I remember." Yes, it's the one from the birthday.
そうなんですよ
That's right.
そして
And...
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
桜、そしてシュシュは添えるだけ
Cherry blossoms, and the scrunchie is just an accessory.
シュシュは添えるだけなんですけど。あ、やばいやばいやばいやばい
The scrunchie is just an accessory. Oh, wait wait wait...
ソファに沈み込んじゃった
I'm sinking into the sofa.
そう、というわけでね
Right, so anyway...
今回は久しぶりに桜ステージに来ました
This time, I've come back to the Sakura Stage after a while.
みんな知ってます？
Do you all know?
ロボ子花見嫌いなんですけど
I actually dislike cherry blossom viewing...
ここのバーチャル桜は大好きなんですよ
...but I love these virtual cherry blossoms.
そう、シュシュはこれ添えるだけ、ショートバージョンのやつ
Yeah, this scrunchie is just an accessory, the short version one.
可愛いでしょ？
Isn't it cute?
ちょっと何か帽子に見える、帽子に見える。あ、これはおさなーいでね
It kind of looks like a hat. It looks like a hat. Ah, that's "childish", isn't it?
そう、花見は嫌いなんです、バーチャルは好きなんですけどね
Yeah, I dislike real cherry blossom viewing, though I like virtual ones.
そう、花粉があるからロボ子は嫌いなんです。そう
Yeah, it's because of the pollen that I dislike it. Right.
はい、じゃあね、次の曲もね
Alright, then, the next song...
まだまだあるので聴いてってほしいです
...there are still more, so I'd like you to listen.
次も、まあ
Next up is, well...
お花にまつわるっちゃお花にまつわるけど、ちょっと切ないかもしれない
It's related to flowers, but it might be a bit sad.
というわけで、聴いてください
So, please listen.
ドライフラワー
Dry Flower.
多分、私じゃなくていいね
Probably, it doesn't have to be me.
余裕のない二人だったし
We were both overwhelmed.
気付けば喧嘩ばかりしてさ
And before we knew it, all we did was fight.
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
ずっと話そうと思ってた
I'd been thinking of talking to you forever.
きっと私たち合わないね
We're surely not a good match.
二人きりしかいない部屋でさ
In a room with just the two of us...
貴方ばかり話していたよね
...you were the only one talking.
もし、いつか
If, someday...
どこかで会えたら
...if we could meet somewhere...
今日のこと笑ってくれるかな
...I wonder if you'd laugh about today.
理由もちゃんと話せないけれど
I can't even explain the reason properly, but...
貴方が眠った後に
...after you fall asleep...
泣くのは嫌
...I hate crying.
声も顔も
Your voice, your face...
不器用なとこも
...even your clumsy parts...
全部、全部
...all of them, all of them...
嫌いじゃないの
...I don't dislike them.
ドライフラワーみたい
Like a dry flower...
君との日々も
...my days with you too...
きっと、きっと、きっと、きっと色褪せる
...will surely, surely, surely, surely fade away.
多分、君じゃなくてよかった
Probably, I'm glad it wasn't you.
惑わされることもないし
I won't be led astray anymore.
私ばかりなんて言葉もなくなった
Words like "it's only me" are gone too.
あんなに悲しい別れでも
Even such a sad breakup...
時間が経てば忘れてく
...we'll forget as time passes.
新しい人と並ぶ君は
Beside someone new, you...
ちゃんと上手くやれているのかな
...are you doing alright?
もう顔も見たくないからさ
Because I don't want to see your face anymore...
変に連絡してこないでほしい
...I hope you don't contact me randomly.
都合がいいのは変わってないんだね
Your selfishness hasn't changed, has it?
でも無視できずに
But I can't ignore you...
また少し返事
...and reply just a little.
声も顔も
Your voice, your face...
不器用なとこも たぶん 今も
Even your awkward side, probably even now...
嫌いじゃないの
I don't hate it.
ドライフラワーみたいに
Just like a dried flower,
時間が経てば きっと きっと きっと きっと
as time passes, surely, surely, surely, surely,
色褪せる
it will fade away.
月明かりに魔物が揺れる
Monsters sway in the moonlight,
きっと私もどうかしてる
I'm surely going crazy too.
暗闇に色彩が浮かぶ
Colors emerge in the darkness.
赤き広がる胸の奥
Red spreads deep within my chest,
ずっとあなたの名前を呼ぶ
I'll always call your name.
好きという気持ちも香る
The feeling of love is also fragrant.
声も 顔も 不器用なとこも
Your voice, your face, your awkward side...
全部 全部 大嫌いだよ
I hate it all, I hate it all.
まだ枯れない花を君に添えてさ
Offering you a flower that hasn't withered yet,
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと
always, always, always, always...
抱えてよ
please hold on to it.
ずっと ずっと...
Always, always...
はい、というわけで「はなびら」でした。
All right, so that was "Hanabira."
聴いてくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you for listening.
あ、やべ、ちょっと待って、間違えた。「ドライフラワー」でした。
Oh, shoot, wait a second. I made a mistake. That was "Dry Flower."
間違えた。次の...いや、いや、いや...
My mistake. The next... no, no, no...
「はなびら」綺麗だなって思っただけです。あ。
I just thought the flower petals were beautiful. Ah.
いや、すごい、花びら綺麗ですね。
Man, the flower petals are so pretty.
「ドライフラワー」歌わせていただきました。
I sang "Dry Flower."
あ、やべ、次の曲言うちゃった。
Oh, crap, I accidentally said the next song's name.
はい。実はね、ロボ子はね、この曲は割と最近覚えた曲なんだけど、
Right. Actually, I only learned this song quite recently,
もうね、すごい「赤き広がる胸の奥」のところから、すごい実はリズムが嵌まって、
but from the "Red spreads deep within my chest" part, I really liked the rhythm.
もうすぐに覚えた曲なんですけれど、
I learned it in no time.
時間経ってから歌えて、すごい良かったです。
I'm really glad I could sing it after all this time.
なんかたまにスパムみたいなコメントあるけど、スパムじゃないのかな? 大丈夫かな? バレへんバレへん。
There are some comments that look like spam, but they aren't, right? Is it okay? No one will notice.
うん! 忘れろビーム! 忘れてください、じゃあ。
Yep! Forget-it-Beam! Please forget what I said, then.
じゃあ、今みんなが忘れたって言うことで、次の曲行きたいと思います。
Now that everyone has forgotten, I'd like to move on to the next song.
じゃあ、次はね、もうライブで歌った、すごい思い出のある曲です。
The next one is a song I've sung at a live before, and it holds a lot of memories.
じゃあ聴いてください。「はなびら」。
Please listen. "Hanabira."
はなびら
作詞・作曲：奥華子
Hanabira (Flower Petal)
Lyrics & Composition: Hanako Oku
一人きり見上げていた
I was looking up all by myself...
あの雲はすぐに消えてた
...at that cloud that vanished so quickly.
寂しさはいつも隣で
Loneliness was always by my side...
私だけ見ていてくれた
...and watched over only me.
人はなぜ形求めて
Why do people seek tangible forms...
逢いたいと願うのでしょう
...and wish to meet?
大切なあなたがいつも
May you, who are precious to me...
笑ってて
...always be smiling.
教えたげ
I'll tell you
誰かじゃなくて
That it's not just anyone
あなたじゃなければ
But that it has to be you
そんなこと初めて
You're the first person
思えた人
Who's ever made me feel that way
あなたに出会えなければ
If I had never met you
この空の青さも 知らないまま
I never would have known how blue the sky is
ありがとうって伝えたい
I want to say thank you
信じられるよ
I can believe it now
泣いてもいいよ
That it's okay to cry
儚き愛おしい日々
In these fleeting, precious days
眠れない 夜の隙間に
In the gaps of a sleepless night
少しだけ 涙こぼれた
A few tears began to fall
不器用につないだ手は
The hand I clumsily held
今もまだ優しくて
Is still so kind even now
あなたが名前を呼んでくれたとき
When you called out my name
初めて自分を 好きになれたの
I was able to like myself for the first time
花びら舞い散るように
Like petals dancing as they fall
あなたがそばにいてくれたから
It's because you were there by my side
大丈夫って伝えたい
I want to say I'm okay
強くなれるよ ひとりじゃ見えない
I can be strong now, because I found a view
景色を見つけたから
That I could never have seen alone
さよならが言えなくても
Even if I can't say goodbye
悲しみが消えなくても
Even if the sadness doesn't fade
大切な時の流れ
In the precious flow of time
今を生きて笑っていて
Live for the now and keep smiling
あなたに出会えなければ
If I had never met you
優しさも強さも 知らないまま
I never would have known kindness or strength
ありがとうって伝えたい
I want to say thank you
信じられるよ 明日の私を
I can believe in the person I'll be tomorrow
儚き愛おしい日々
In these fleeting, precious days
はい、というわけで、『はなびら』でした。
All right, and that was "Hanabira."
思い出してくれた人いますかね？
Did anyone remember it?
ライブで歌った、思い出のある曲です。
It's a song filled with memories that I've sung at lives before.
ネタバレじゃなかったよ。
It wasn't a spoiler!
拍手もいっぱいありがとう。
Thank you so much for all the applause.
スタンプもね、メンバーさんいっぱい使ってくれてありがとうね。
And members, thank you for using so many stamps.
嬉しい、可愛い。
I'm so happy, they're so cute.
Thank you! Thank you so much!
ぱちぱちぱちぱち。
Clap clap clap clap.
というわけで、なんと！もう50分になってしまった。
And so, believe it or not! It's already 50 minutes past.
というわけで、ロボ子、告知してもいいですかー？
With that said, may Roboco make an announcement?
はい！では、今回、告知がなんとあります！
Yes! So, I have an announcement this time!
それはですね、こちら！ドドン！
And that would be this! Drumroll!
ロボ子さん活動三周年記念！というわけで本日3月20日土曜日の、えー、20時...
Roboco-san's 3rd anniversary! So, today, Saturday, March 20th, at, er, 8:00 PM...
活動三周年記念
3rd Anniversary Commemoration
1時から...
Starting from 1:00...
嘘ついた、へへへ...
I'm lying, hehe...
22時からですね、22時から...
It's from 22:00, from 22:00...
ボイスのね、販売をします。
We'll be selling the voice packs.
なんと今回のほうね、ボイス、
And for this time's voice packs,
記念ボイス。こちらのボイスは全部ASMRとなっております。
the commemorative voices are all ASMR.
ASMRのシチュエーションのボイスと、そして、Blue_Gk先生、
There are ASMR situation voices, and also, by Blue_Gk-sensei,
ブル先生のね、二層印刷のアクリルブロック、
Bull-sensei's acrylic blocks with two-layer printing,
そして同じくブル先生のアクリルキーホルダーとなっております。
and also acrylic keyholders by Bull-sensei.
えー、こちら全部セットの特典では、ブル先生のね、
And as a bonus for the full set, Bull-sensei's...
えー、箔押し複製サイン入りのポストカードが、なんとついてきます！
foil-stamped reproduction signed postcard is included!
めちゃめちゃ可愛いんだけど。
It's super cute.
ちょっとさ、もう左側で、あのーもうわかっちゃってるんだけど、
Well, you can already see it on the left, but...
アクリルブロックが一体どういうの？っていうと、こちらですね。
what's an acrylic block like? Let me show you.
説明をドドン！
Ta-da!
はい！こんなの！立体的なの！可愛くない？これ。
Yes! Like this! It's 3D! Isn't it cute?
もうね、2種類のやつがあるんですけれども、
There are two types available,
両方ともブル先生に描いていただきました。
and Bull-sensei illustrated both of them.
めちゃめちゃ可愛いんだ、へへへ。ニヤニヤしちゃうんだけど。
They're so cute, hehe. I can't stop grinning.
そう。で、今回実はですね、あのー花びら、どうしてこの衣装にしたかっていうと、
Right. And actually, about why I chose this outfit with the petals...
この衣装をね、合わせたかったっていうのが、あるので、
it's because I wanted it to match this outfit.
潤み目、うさ耳、リボン、ポニーテール、
Moist eyes, rabbit ears, a ribbon, a ponytail,
そしてお正月衣装。こちらですね。
and this New Year's outfit. This is it.
こんな感じのやつです。可愛いでしょ。
It looks like this. Cute, right?
そう、この衣装にしたんです。
Yes, I went with this outfit.
そして、なんとね、もう一個のほうはね、メイドさん。
And the other one is a maid!
やっぱね、3周年記念はお祝い事だからさ、いっぱいね、
After all, the 3rd anniversary is a celebration, so...
お菓子食べたいなってことで、欲張りセットです。
I wanted to eat lots of sweets. It's a "greedy" set.
ドバ耳じゃない、うさ耳なんだよね。
Not "doba" ears, they're rabbit ears.
そう。猫耳メイドさんのアクリルキーホルダーとなっております。
Right. It's an acrylic keyholder of a cat-eared maid.
めっちゃ可愛いでしょ。こちらなんとね、えー、
Isn't it super cute? And actually,
もう50分になった時点で、実はBoothさんのほうで発表されております。
they've already been announced on Booth at the 50-minute mark.
あ、運営さんがお手が早いことに、えー、今更新していただくと、
Oh, the staff were quick. If you refresh now,
概要欄のほうにリンクが出てきている模様なので、ぜひぜひ見てみてください。
it seems the links are appearing in the description, so please check them out.
で、こちらのほうは、今はまだカートに購入っていうのはできないんですけれども、
As for these, you can't put them in your cart and buy them just yet, but...
22時になったら、えー、買えるようになっておりますね。
at 22:00, you'll be able to buy them.
みんなぜひ購入してくれよな。
Everyone, please make sure to get them.
可愛いだろ、ゲットしてくれよな。
They're cute, right? Go get them.
ASMRのほうはね、今回3種類なんですけれども、
There are three types of ASMR this time,
ボイスのほう、シチュエーションを収録してみました。
I recorded several situations for the voices.
KU100で撮ってみて、音は結構いいと思います。へへへ。
I used a KU100, so I think the sound quality is quite good. Hehehe.
でもね、ちょっと今回は、聞いてもらいたいなっていう感じですね。
But this time, I really want you to listen to them.
ちょっとシチュエーションをロボ子が考えたんだけど、
Roboco thought of the situations,
ちょっとノリと勢いでやってしまったんだけど、
but I might have done it a bit too much on impulse...
これはまた生放送で詳しく、またみんなと話せたらいいなと思ってます。
but I hope I can talk about it in more detail with everyone during a live stream.
そう、見て、ほら、笑顔バージョン。可愛いでしょ。
Right, look, look, it's the smiling version. Isn't it cute?
これ、こんな感じ。スッて。スッて感じです。
Like this. *Swish*. Just like that.
可愛い。可愛いロボ子も早く飾りたいな。あ、見て、しかも。
Cute. I want to put up the cute Roboco soon too. Oh, look!
今回サインがね、なんと、あの、いつものひらがなじゃなくて、
This time, the signature isn't in the usual hiragana...
ローマ字になっています。
it's in romaji.
ASMR、なんかさ、ちょっと、え？みたいな感じのタイトルがあるの、気づいた？
Did you notice there's an ASMR title that's a bit like... "Wait, what?"
あれ、本当すごい迷ったんだけど、言っちゃいました。
I was really unsure about that one, but I said it.
タイトルだけちょっと「え」なんだけど、全然そんなことないんで、
Only the title is a bit "eh?", but it's not like that at all.
あのー全人類聴けるやつなんで、ぜひぜひ聴いてみてね。
Anyone can listen to it, so please give it a listen.
高性能になれます、あの薬は。そうなんです。
That "medicine" will make you high-performance. It's true.
あ。
Ah.
あ、あ、先生、あのー... 懺悔タイムいいですか？
Ah, ah, Sensei, um... Can I have a confession time?
あのー... あの、あの、懺悔、懺悔タイムしていい？
Um... can I have a confession, a confession time?
うぇー、これ後で変えてください。あの、ロボ子は...
Uwah, please change this later. Um, Roboco...
実は「K」じゃなくて、「C」なんですよ。ロボコの「コ」は「C」なんですよ。
actually, it's not "K", it's "C". The "ko" in Roboco is with a "C".
あー、やっちゃった！高性能、
Ah, I messed up! High-performance...
ロボ子まだ高性能になる薬飲んでないからさ、まだポンコツなんだよ。
Roboco hasn't taken the medicine to become high-performance yet, so I'm still a klutz.
そう、これは、後で、サインちょっと、変えます。
Right, so I'll change the signature a bit later.
というわけで、みんな今だけですよ、「KO」で見れるのは。
So, everyone, it's only for now that you can see "KO".
ノリと勢いで書いたら、「K」って書いちゃった。
I wrote it with so much energy that I ended up writing "K".
今はポンコツでも許してあげる。でも後で、高性能になるもん。
Forgive me for being a klutz right now. But later, I'll become high-performance.
ロボ子も、みんなもね、
Roboco, and everyone too,
あの、R-O-B-O-T-T-Oみたいに、間違えないでね。
don't mistake it like 'R-O-B-O-T-T-O', okay?
ロボットはR-O-B-O-Tだし、
'Robot' is R-O-B-O-T,
ロボ子はR-O-B-O-C-Oなのでね、
and 'Roboco' is R-O-B-O-C-O,
みんな、覚えとくんだぞ。ロボ子との約束な。
so everyone, remember that. It's a promise with Roboco.
もう、これだけね、
I mean, with this much,
これだけわざと間違えればみんなもね、間違えないでしょう。うん。
if I mistake it on purpose this much, you won't mistake it, right? Yeah.
というわけで、あと2分なんだけど、
So, there's 2 minutes left,
これ歌ってる途中で、なっちゃうな。
but it'll run out while I'm singing.
ぜひ聞いてみて... 聞いて、じゃないや、
Please try listening... not listening,
えっと、購入してみて下さい。はい。
um, please try purchasing it. Yes.
それではね、最後は、
Well then, for the last one,
もう最近のすごいお気に入りの曲、締めていきたいと思います。
I'd like to close with a song I've really liked recently.
これは、もうね、温かくなる曲で、
This is a song that makes you feel warm,
最後終わりたかったので、温かくなる曲を歌いたいと思います。
and since I wanted to end with it, I'll sing it for you.
それでは、聞いて下さい。「ぎゅっと」。
Well then, please listen. 'Gyutto'.
ぎゅっと
作詞・作曲：もさを。
Gyutto
Lyrics & Composition: Mosawo.
ねえ 手をつなぐと体温が伝わって
Hey, when we hold hands, I can feel your warmth
無邪気な顔につられて
Influenced by your innocent face
変なくせ真似してみたり
I try to mimic your weird habits
寝顔じっと眺めていたら
While staring at your sleeping face
いつの間にか朝になってたり
Before I knew it, morning had come
特別はたまにでいいよ
Special occasions can be rare
何気ない日常が
My casual everyday life
私にとって大切で
Is precious to me
そばにいるだけでわかるの
Just by being by your side, I can tell
心からあなたが好きなんだ
I truly love you
素直になれないわがままな私
The selfish me who can't be honest
だけど だからね
But, that's why
あなたの大きな身体でぎゅっと
Hug me tight with your big body
抱き寄せて離さないで
Hold me close and don't let go
柔らかくて優しい声で
With your soft and gentle voice
私の名前呼んで
Call my name
それだけで私は幸せだから
That alone makes me happy
ひとつ願いが叶うのなら
If one wish could come true
あなたとこれからもずっと
I hope to be by your side
ずっと隣にいれますように
Forever and ever from now on
ふと落ち込んだり
Sometimes I feel down
嫌なことで泣いていても
Even if I'm crying over something bad
大丈夫だよって 一番近くで支えてくれたね
You supported me from the closest point, saying "it's okay"
そっと包み込んでくれる
You gently wrap around me
私の弱いところ知ってるみたいに
As if you know my weaknesses
いつも隣にいてくれる あなたのおかげで
Thanks to you, who is always by my side
そばにいるだけで落ち着くの
Just being near you calms me down
あなたの彼女で幸せだって
I'm happy being your girlfriend
こぼれそうな好きの気持ち受け取ってくれるかな
Will you accept these overflowing feelings of love?
ねえ あなたの大きな身体でぎゅっと
Hey, hug me tight with your big body
抱き寄せて離さないで
Hold me close and don't let go
柔らかくて優しい声で
With your soft and gentle voice
私の名前呼んで
Call my name
それだけで私は幸せだから
That alone makes me happy
ひとつ願いが叶うのなら
If one wish could come true
あなたとこれからもずっと
I hope to be by your side
ずっと隣にいれますように
Forever and ever from now on
もしもこの先喧嘩しても
Even if we have fights in the future
価値観が擦れ違っても
Even if our values clash
二人で乗り越えていこうね
Let's overcome them together
全部全部ぎゅっと
All of it, tightly
ぎゅっと
Gyutto
私がぎゅっとさせてね
Let me hold you tight
ひとつだけ伝えたいことがある
There's just one thing I want to tell you
これからもずっと大好きだよ
I will always love you from now on
はい、というわけで
Alright, and so...
最後は「ぎゅっと」歌いました。
for the last song, I sang "Gyutto."
結構ガチ恋距離を意識して
I was aiming for a "serious crush" distance
カメラ回してもらったんですけど
with the camera movements,
どうでしたか皆さん？
how was it, everyone?
みんな、どうだった？
Everyone, how was it?
ガチ恋した？
Did you fall for me?
基本ガチ恋しないキャラだけど
I'm usually not the type for that,
ガチ恋した？本当？嬉しい。
but did you? Really? I'm happy.
はい、というわけで
Alright, and so...
なんともう22時に、22時になってるので
since it's already 10 PM,
実は帰ります。
I'm actually going home.
みんなBOOTHぜひぜひ購入してってくれよな！
Everyone, please be sure to buy the merch on BOOTH!
購入してくれますか？
Will you buy it?
ガチ恋した？好きになりそう？
Did you fall for me? Might fall in love?
嬉しい。
I'm happy.
今日初めて見た人もね、いると思うので
Since there are people seeing me for the first time,
初めましての方もね、気に入ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if those newcomers like it.
スパチャもいっぱいありがとう。
Thanks for all the Super Chats.
今度いっぱい読ませてね。ありがとう。
Let me read them all later. Thank you.
星マークも可愛い。
The star mark is cute too.
買ったよ？
You bought it?
本当？はやっ！
Really? That was fast!
はやっ！歌声本当好き？
Fast! You really like my singing voice?
バラードライブ嬉しい、ありがとう。
I'm glad you liked the ballad live, thank you.
そうというわけでね、ロボ子も
And so, Roboco has actually...
実は本当に３周年で...
...reached her 3rd anniversary...
しかもあと一点何ヶ月ぐらいとかしたらね...
And in another month and a bit or so...
ロボ子、年を取るんですよ
Roboco will get older,
また一歳。
another year.
なんと憧れの５歳になれるので。
I'll finally be the 5-year-old I've longed to be.
次の誕生日が実はとっても楽しみ。
I'm actually looking forward to my next birthday very much.
みんな、５月の２３日はね...
Everyone, on May 23rd...
また別のことが色々できると思うので...
I think we'll be able to do various other things...
楽しみにしてて下さいね。
So please look forward to it.
そう、今ロボ子は４歳なんです。
That's right, Roboco is currently 4 years old.
そう、今４歳で、みんなと３年間ね
Yes, I'm 4 now, and after 3 years...
一緒に配信をやってて...
...of streaming together with everyone...
ホロライブもすごいいっぱい増えてって...
Hololive has grown so much too...
もうなんだろうね...
How should I say...
感慨、感慨深いんだけど...
...it's deeply moving...
この前もちょっとちらっと言ったから...
I mentioned it briefly before...
何言おうかな、何言おうかなって
I was really wondering what to say,
すごい悩んでしまったんだけど...
and I was really torn...
ロボ子は、その３周年をね
By reaching this 3rd anniversary,
迎えたことによって...
Roboco...
バラードライブもね、実現できたので...
...was able to realize this ballad live...
実・現できたので、もう本当にすごい嬉しいです。
I was able to realize it, so I'm truly very happy.
あ、そうしんのすけとタメになるの。
Ah, right, I'll be the same age as Shinnosuke.
しんのすけとタメになる。嬉しい。
Same age as Shinnosuke. I'm happy.
そう、七五三ちゃんと行こうね。
Right, let's go celebrate Shichi-Go-San properly.
エッヘン！行けちゃうもんね。
Ahem! I can go, after all.
そう、実現できたのでね...
So, since I was able to realize it...
まだまだね、ライブはね
The live shows will continue...
色々...
to be varied...
実験じゃないよ？実現ね。
It's not an experiment? I meant realization.
そう、もう年長さんなの。
Yes, I'm already in the oldest group.
そうなんだよ。
That's right.
もういっぱい、本当は、本当はこのご時世じゃなかったら...
There's so much... actually, if it wasn't for the current situation...
誰かをお呼びして
I was thinking of inviting someone
一緒にやるっていうことを考えてたんだけど...
and doing it together...
やっぱりこのご時世だったから
But because of the current situation,
ロボ子オンリーのソロのバラードライブに
it ended up being a Roboco-only solo
なってしまったんだけど...
ballad live...
今度はね、ご時世が終わったら...
Next time, when things settle down...
ちゃんとゲストも呼んで
I want to invite guests properly
デュエットもありでライブがしたいと思ってます、ロボ子は。
and have duets in my live shows.
なので、これで終わりじゃなくて...
So, this isn't the end...
これはロボ子のYouTubeの中での
this is just my first live show
ファーストライブっていうことで...
on YouTube...
セカンドの時は、誰かを呼べたら嬉しいなって思う！
so I hope I can invite someone for the second one!
だから、医療系頑張ってくれ！
So, medical professionals, please do your best!
もう！
Geez!
次はね、デュエットをやりたいです！はい！
Next time, I want to do a duet! Yes!
それでは皆さん、今日はロボ子の
And so everyone, thank you for coming
バラードライブにきてくれてありがとうございました！
to Roboco's ballad live today!
いっぱいスクショとか
Please be sure to look at all
ぜひぜひ見てってくれよな！
the screenshots and everything!
感想とかロボ子あとで見に行くからね！
Roboco will go look at your impressions later!
それではみんな、次の配信で会いましょう！
Well then everyone, see you in the next stream!
さようなら！
Goodbye!
おつロボ！
Otsu-Robo!
Thank you for watching!
Thank you for... bye bye!
ロボ子さん 全身3D 3周年記念 バラードLIVE Robot Memory
Roboco-san Full Body 3D 3rd Anniversary Ballad LIVE Robot Memory